"I have nothing to wear!"
“我没什么可穿的！”
You might have said to yourself, feeling slightly distressed, wardrobe door wide open, hours before going to a party or important event.
你可能在参加一个派对或重要活动的前几个小时，看着敞开的衣柜门，略带苦恼地对自己说过这句话。
Casual or formal?
穿休闲装还是正装呢？
Is this too flamboyant?
这件是不是太张扬了？
Should I look more demure?
我是不是应该看起来更端庄些呢？
How strictly should we follow fashion rules?
我们应该多严格地遵循时尚规则呢？
'Never mix patterns' is one of them.
“永远不要混搭图案”就是其中一条规则。
Clashing prints might make Coco Chanel spin in her grave but gets the seal of approval of some stylists nowadays.
相互冲突的印花图案可能会让可可·香奈儿在九泉之下不得安宁，但如今却得到了一些造型师的认可。
"It's edgy," says Martine Alexander, adviser to British TV actresses.
“这很前卫。”
"Matching everything makes you look like you've tried too hard.
英国电视女演员的顾问玛蒂娜·亚历山大说，“把所有东西都搭配得严丝合缝会让你看起来用力过猛。
Style should look effortless."
时尚风格应该看起来毫不费力。”
Well, just be careful not to make people's eyes go funny when they look at you, I say.
嗯，我觉得还是要小心点，别让别人看你的时候觉得辣眼睛。
Men have the issue of white socks.
男士们有白色袜子的问题。
"Unless you're exercising there is absolutely no appropriate moment to wear white socks," says Alex Bilmes, editor of the men's magazine Esquire.
“除非你在运动，否则任何时刻穿白色袜子都不太合适。”男士杂志《君子》的编辑亚历克斯·比尔姆斯说。
And he adds: "These types of rules exist to make sure fashion innocents don't make such a bad mistake."
他还补充道：“这些规则的存在是为了确保那些时尚小白不会犯这么严重的错误。”
We all know that white socks are usually bulky and may look cheap.
我们都知道白色袜子通常比较臃肿，而且可能看起来很廉价。
But there's a long British tradition of men wearing socks with sandals so... Maybe critics should put a sock in it and let us wear what we are comfortable with.
但是英国一直有男士穿凉鞋配袜子的传统，所以……也许批评者们应该闭嘴，让我们穿自己觉得舒服的衣服。
When you look a particular way you are sending a message about yourself.
当你以某种特定的方式打扮自己时，你就在传达关于你自己的信息。
It's not a good idea to go to a job interview wearing shorts or showing too much cleavage.
穿着短裤去参加工作面试或者露出太多乳沟可不是个好主意。
Or going to the market in your pyjamas.
穿着睡衣去市场也不行。
But, whatever you wear, do it with confidence.
但是，无论你穿什么，都要自信地去穿。
Designer Gianni Versace said it all: "Don't be into trends.
设计师詹尼·范思哲说得很到位：“不要追逐潮流。
Don't make fashion own you, but you decide what you are, and what you want to express, by the way you dress and the way you live."
不要让时尚主宰你，而是你要通过自己的穿着方式和生活方式来决定你是谁，以及你想要表达什么。”